# Jialin Sun

Email: jialinsun4815162342@gmail.com Telephone: +86 16651694296

Homepage: <a href="https://nick0317sun.github.io/">https://nick0317sun.github.io/</a>

### **Short Biography**

Jialin Sun (孙嘉麟) received his master's degree in Land Use and Information Technology from China Agricultural University. He is currently a research assistant at the <u>Urban Environmental Monitoring and Modeling laboratory</u>, led by <u>Prof. Xuecao Li</u>. He has a strong interdisciplinary background in remote sensing, geography, agriculture, and artificial intelligence. His current research focuses on urban sustainability and urban ecology. Specifically, he is studying the visual accessibility of urban greenspaces from buildings of varying heights on a global scale, as well as the generation of high-resolution, hourly land surface temperature products for cities worldwide.

#### **Education**

09/2022 - 07/2024	China Agricultural University	
	Master in Land Use and Information Technology	
	• GPA: 3.61/4 (Rank 2/14)	
09/2018 - 06/2022	Nanjing University of Information Science and Technology	
	Bachelor in Remote Sensing Science and Technology	

#### **Research Interests**

- Urban sustainability and ecology
- Urban greenery and urban heat
- Environmental remote sensing
- Land use and land cover mapping
- Multi-source data fusion, time series analysis
- Machine learning, deep learning

## **Research Experiences**

Evaluating the visual accessibility of urban greenspaces from different building heights on a global scale

#### Supervised independent research

07/2024 - present

- Develop an efficient method to calculate the green view index (GVI) of different building heights.
- Evaluate the visual accessibility of urban greenspaces across different cities worldwide.
- **★ Duty:** Methodology design, implementation, analysis, writing and reviewing.

# Generating a worldwide high spatial resolution hourly land surface temperature product for urban areas

#### Supervised independent research

07/2024 – present

- Develop a high spatial resolution, hourly LST data generation framework using ECOSTRESS LST data, as well as other multi-source datasets.
- Apply the framework globally to generate a valid product.
- **★ Duty:** Methodology design, implementation, analysis, writing and reviewing.

# Research on Segment Anything Model (SAM)-Assisted remote sensing crop mapping \*Independent research\*\* 05/2023 -06/2024

# (1) Enhancing crop mapping through an automated sample generation framework based on SAM

- Evaluate the performance of SAM for crop parcel segmentation using medium-resolution satellite imagery, such as Sentinel-2 and Landsat-8.
- Develop a novel automated sample generation framework based on SAM.

#### (2) A weakly supervised learning method based on SAM for crop mapping (Master's thesis)

- Use adapters to finetune SAM for crop parcel segmentation in Sentinel-2 images.
- Generate high-quality pseudo labels through finetuned SAM and weak annotations, replacing the labor-intensive process of obtaining pixel-level annotations.
- Apply pseudo labels to train a fully supervised segmentation model for crop mapping.
- ★ Duty: Methodology design, implementation, analysis, writing and reviewing.

# Large-scale crop mapping with multi-source satellite images using a spatiotemporal datacube-based deep learning framework

#### Supervised independent research

10/2022 - 05/2023

- Develop a datacube-based framework to conduct large-scale crop mapping.
- Adopt a novel sample extraction technique based on spatiotemporal datacube.
- Fuse GF-1 and Sentinel-2 multi-temporal images by early and late fusion strategies.
- ★ **Duty:** Implementation, analysis, writing and reviewing.

#### **FY-4 LPW product authenticity validation**

#### Supervised independent research

10/2021 - 03/2022

- Validate FY-4 layer precipitable water product using radiosonde data.
- **★ Duty:** Implementation and analysis.

## **Teaching Experiences**

#### **GIS** Application and Development (China Agricultural University)

**2023 Spring** 

★ **Duty:** Teach geospatial data processing based on Python.

#### **Publications**

#### In preparation

- [1] Quantifying visual accessibility of greenery in urban buildings from a three-dimensional perspective: An empirical approach.
- [2] Generating 70 m, hourly, all-weather land surface temperature for urban regions based on ECOSTRESS and reanalysis data.

#### 2024

- [1] <u>Sun J</u>, Yan S, Yao X, et al. <u>A Segment Anything Model based weakly supervised learning method for crop mapping using Sentinel-2 time series images[J]. International Journal of Applied Earth Observation and Geoinformation, 2024, 133: 104085.</u>
- [2] <u>Sun J</u>, Yan S, Alexandridis T, et al. <u>Enhancing Crop Mapping through Automated Sample Generation Based on Segment Anything Model with Medium-Resolution Satellite Imagery</u>[J]. Remote Sensing, 2024, 16(9): 1505.
- [3] Yan S, Yao X, <u>Sun J</u>, et al. <u>TSANet: A deep learning framework for the delineation of agricultural fields utilizing satellite image time series</u>[J]. Computers and Electronics in Agriculture, 2024, 220: 108902.
- [4] <u>Sun J</u>, Yao X, Yan S, et al. <u>Large-scale crop mapping based on multi-source remote sensing intelligent interpretation: A spatiotemporal data cubes approach</u>[J]. IEEE Journal of Selected Topics in Applied Earth Observations and Remote Sensing, 2024.

#### **Awards and Honors**

•	Excellent undergraduate thesis	2022
•	First Prize of Academic Scholarship (NUIST)	2019, 2020
•	Mary English Scholarship (NUIST)	2019

#### **Skills**

- Computer manipulation: Python, MATLAB, IDL, Linux, high-performance computing, Google Earth Engine.
- Software: ArcMap, ArcGIS pro, ENVI, SNAP.

### Language

- Mandarin (native)
- English (fluent)